Guide to the Jazz Loft Project Records, 1950-2012 and undated RL.10001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Associated Audiovisual Materials, 1967-2010 and undated; 1; 210 items
  - Jazz Loft Project Radio Series Sampler, 2009; 79
    - Sampler Jazz Loft Project Radio Series Promotional Copy. Not for broadcast. Not for sale., 2009, Compact disc (Box 31, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0077)
  - Jazz Loft Radio Project Hall Overton rough draft, 2008 June 13; 80
    - Overton-Rough; 6/13/08; Fishko, 2008 June 13, Compact disc (Box 32, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0113)
  - Jazz Loft Radio Project NEH Pilot, 2008 January 14; 81
    - Jazz Loft Radio Project NEH Pilot; Sara Fishko; 1.14.08; 13:30, 2008 January 14, Compact disc (Box 32, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0112)
  - Jazz Loft Sampler, 2005 March; 82
    - Jazz Loft Sampler 3/05 Vidipax event, 2005 March, Compact disc (Box 32, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0105)
  - Jazz Loft Sounds Playlist #1, undated; 83
    - Jazz Loft Sounds Playlist #1 "Walter Trego", undated, Compact disc (Box 34, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0179)
  - Jeffrey, Paul oral history, undated; 84
    - Paul Jeffrey (illegible) 9/27/07, undated, Compact disc (Box 35, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0213)
  - Jim Turner: Poet and Peasant, undated; 85
    - Jim Turner; Poet and Peasant; Jazz Piano Solos, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0302)
  - Jim Turner's Jelly Roll Blues: A Tribute to "Jelly Roll" Morton, undated; 86
    - Jim Turner's Jelly Roll Blues: A Tribute to "Jelly Roll" Morton; with Guest Artists Topsy Chapman, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0301)
  - Jimmy Raney Quintet, undated; 87
    - Jimmy Raney Quintet/Jimmy Raney Swings and Strings, undated, audio-cassette (Box 24, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0142)
  - Just for Fun, undated; 88
    - Charles Fox and his charanga play; Just for Fun, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0277)
  - Kronos Quartet on Monk, undated; 89
    - Kronos on Monk 9/15/07, undated, Compact disc (Box 31, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0091)
  - Kronos Quartet--Following Monk, undated; 90
    - Following Monk Kronos 9/15/07 Jazz Loft, undated, Compact disc (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0263)
  - Lennie Tristano and the New Tristano, undated; 91
    - Lennie Tristano & the New Tristano, undated, Compact disc (Box 31, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0093)
  - Live at the Garage-The Howard Williams Band, undated; 92
    - Live at the Garage-The Howard Williams Band, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0303)
  - Loft Footage, 2004 August 19; 93
    - 2 Min. of Loft Footage, 8-14-04, Loft from Roof, 2 min. Pan of 8/9, 2004 August 19, Mini-dv videocassette (Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0130)
  - Loft Recordings Comparison, 2004 April; 94
    - W. Eugene Smith Archive Loft Recordings 821 Sixth Ave. New York City 1957-1964; Comparison of Original vs. Mastered and Restored Selections, 2004 April, Compact disc (Box 34, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0176)
  - Loft Recordings Comparison, 2004 April; 95
    - W. Eugene Smith Archive Loft Recordings 821 Sixth Ave. New York City 1957-1964; Comparison of Original vs. Mastered and Restored Selections, 2004 April, Compact disc (Box 34, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0177)
  - Lois Deloatch interview, undated; 96
    - Lois D mp3, undated, Compact disc (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0254)
  - Long John Nebel: Way Out World, undated; 97
    - LJN: Way Out World, undated, Compact disc (Box 33, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0164)
  - Martial Solal Dodeca Band Plays Ellington, undated; 98
    - Martial Solal Dodeca Band Plays Ellington, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0298)
  - Martin Eagle Trio, Quartet and Solo, undated; 99
    - 1964 Martin Eagle with Barre Phillips-Bass Charles Moffett-Drums-Joel Friedman-Cello, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0274)
  - Masks, undated; 100
    - Masks Jack Reilly, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0294)
  - Mingus Radio Documentary, undated; 101
    - Mingus radio doc by Karen Michel, undated, Compact disc (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0264)
  - Monk at Town Hall, undated; 102
    - Monk at Town Hall, undated, Compact disc (Box 33, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0173)
  - Monk at Town Hall program, undated; 103
    - Monk @ Town Hall Program, undated, Compact disc (Box 34, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0210)
  - Monk, Thelonious-Misterioso, undated; 104
    - Monk Misterioso, undated, Compact disc (Box 31, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0094)
  - Monk/Overton New School Talks, undated; 105
    - Monk/Overton New School Both Talking Tracks (2); 3 & 5 or 7, undated, Compact disc (Box 33, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0171)
  - Monk's Homecoming event, undated; 106
    - Monk's Homecoming; Jeffrey, Williams, Oze, & Moran; 9.20.07; Disc 1 of 2, undated, Compact disc (Box 35, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0248)
    - Monk's Homecoming; Jeffrey, Williams, Oze, & Moran; 9.20.07; Disc 2 of 2, undated, Compact disc (Box 35, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0249)
  - Monk's Moods: Music of Thelonious Monk, undated; 107
    - Monk's Moods Music of Thelonious Monk with Special Guest Steve Lacy; Anthony Brown's Asian American Orchestra, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0268)
  - Moran, Jason, undated; 108
    - Jason Moran wav, undated, Compact disc (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0255)
    - Moran, undated, Compact disc (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0256)
    - Jason Moran wav, undated, Compact disc (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0257)
    - Jason Moran mp3, undated, Compact disc (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0258)
  - Movie Songs Project, undated; 109
    - Movie Songs Project/Royce Campbell Trio plus Phil Woods, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0269)
  - Musical recordings featuring Don Cherry and Eddie Listengardt, undated; 110
    - Don Cherry-Solar; Eddie Listengardt-Solo; Don Cherry-Solo, undated, Compact disc (Box 35, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0216)
  - New Look is the Anxious Look, undated; 111
    - New Look is the Anxious Look, undated, DVD (Box 34, Video-disc RL10001-DVD-0012)
  - Oral History Audio excerpt, undated; 112
    - not labeled, undated, Compact disc (Box 33, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0169)
  - Overton and McKenna dual piano jazz, undated; 113
    - Overton & McKenna dual piano jazz (entirety) 1-7; Hall Overton Jazz Lab Series (7/8 songs) 8-14, undated, Compact disc (Box 33, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0139)
  - Partridge, Dan, 2008 March 24; 114
    - Jazz Loft Podcasts, B-Roll, filmed 03/24/08, A, Mostly Dan Partridge-centered imagery, filmed by Christopher Sims, 2008 March 24, Mini-dv videocassette (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0086)
    - Copy 2 (Good Copy), Jazz Loft Podcasts, A, B-Roll Filmed 3/24/08 copy 2, copied 5/12/09, 2008 March 24, Mini-dv videocassette (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0132)
    - Jazz Loft Podcasts, Partridge Interview, filmed 03/31/08, B, conducted by Sarah Moye & Christopher Sims, Filmed by Christopher Sims, 2008 March 31, Mini-dv videocassette (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0087)
    - Jazz Loft Podcasts, Partridge Interview, filmed 03/31/08, C, conducted by Sarah Moye & Christopher Sims, Filmed by Christopher Sims, Time Code Problems, 2008 March 31, Mini-dv videocassette (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0088)
    - Jazz Loft Podcasts, Partridge Interview, filmed 03/31/08, D, conducted by Sarah Moye & Christopher Sims, filmed by Christopher Sims, 2008 March 31, Mini-dv videocassette (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0089)
  - Pure Passion, undated; 115
    - Pure Passion; Jack Reilly Solo Piano Improvisations; 10 Standards, 6 Originals, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0295)
  - Report on Music: Jazz Panel, undated; 116
    - Report on Music: Jazz Panel; Gene Bruch & Persichetti, Overton, Schuller; Xfer from reel 7 1/2 LPS, undated, Compact disc (Box 33, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0144)
  - Rhythm of a Corner, 2006 July; 117
    - Rhythm of a Corner Sample master July '06, 2006 July, Compact disc (Box 35, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0242)
  - Rhythm of a Corner: W. Eugene Smith's Jazz Loft, 1957-65, undated; 118
    - Rhythm of a Corner: W. Eugene Smith's Jazz Loft, 1957-65; Sample tracks from Smith's audio tapes, W. Eugene Smith Archive, Center for Creative Photography; compiled by Sam Stephenson and Dan Partridge, Center for Documentary Studies, Duke University, undated, Compact disc (Box 35, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0245)
  - Ron Free in 826 Loft, undated; 119
    - Ron Free in 826 Loft Paul's Footage, undated, DVD (Box 34, Video-disc RL10001-DVD-0015)
  - Ron Free Loft Recordings, undated; 120
    - Ron Free Loft Recordings; Jazz Loft Project/CCP; WUNC loan; property of W. Eugene Smith Archive @ CCP, undated, Compact disc (Box 35, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0215)
  - Roy Haynes at Artcenter, undated; 121
    - Roy Haynes at Artcenter, undated, Compact disc (Box 35, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0220)
  - Roy Haynes in Albany and Saratoga, NY, undated; 122
    - Roy Haynes Albany, NY-Saratoga, NY 6/30/02, undated, Compact disc (Box 35, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0226)
  - Sam Stephenson on WSHA, undated; 123
    - Sam Stephenson on WSHA 3/26/07 master, undated, Compact disc (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0253)
  - Sample Jazz Loft Compilation for Bose, 2008 May; 124
    - Sample Jazz Loft Compilation for Bose May 2008; Jazz Loft Project Center for Documentary Studies, 2008 May, Compact disc (Box 35, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0243)
  - Saudy Substitute Track, undated; 125
    - Saudy Substitute Track #8; 4:03; Joel Freedman, undated, Compact disc (Box 34, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0180)
  - Shades of Redd, undated; 126
    - Shades of Redd; Freddie Redd Quintet, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0290)
  - Smith Music, undated; 127
    - Smith music, undated, Compact disc (Box 31, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0060)
  - Teranga, undated; 128
    - Jon Faddis Teranga, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0275)
  - The Blues, undated; 129
    - Martin Scorsese Presents The Blues, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0267)
  - The Charles Fox Songbook, undated; 130
    - The Charles Fox Songbook, undated, DVD (Box 37, Video-disc RL10001-DVD-0016)
  - The Reach of Memory, undated; 131
    - Elmer Gibson; The Reach of Memory, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0280)
  - Thelonious Monk Clips for Lincoln Center, 2008 November; 132
    - Monk clips for Lincoln Center Nov. 08, 2008 November, Compact disc (Box 32, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0122)
  - Town Hall Concerts 2009, undated; 133
    - Town Hall Concerts February 26-27, 2009, undated, Compact disc (Box 34, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0199)
  - Town Hall Concerts 2009--Lauren's Choices, undated; 134
    - Lauren's Choices Town Hall Concerts 2009, undated, Compact disc (Box 34, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0200)
  - Town Hall Concerts 2009--Lauren's Choices II, undated; 135
    - Town Hall Concerts February 2009; Lauren's Choices II, undated, Compact disc (Box 34, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0202)
  - Tribute to Trane, undated; 136
    - The Paul Jeffry Quintet; Tribute to Trane, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0282)
  - Tzu-Jan: The Sound of the Ta'rot Volume 2, undated; 137
    - Tzu-Jan: The sound of the Ta'rot Volume 2; Jack Reilly Solo Piano Improvisations, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0297)
  - Unidentified, 138
    - Mini-dv videocassette (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0133)
    - Mini-dv videocassette (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0134)
    - Mini-dv videocassette (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0135)
    - Mini-dv videocassette (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0136)
    - Mini-dv videocassette (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0137)
    - Mini-dv videocassette (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0138)
    - Mini-dv videocassette (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0139)
    - Mini-dv videocassette (Box 24, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0140)
    - Untitled, undated, Standard audio-cassette (Box 24, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0141)
    - Untitled, undated, Standard audio-cassette (Box 24, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0142)
    - Untitled, undated, Standard audio-cassette (Box 24, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0143)
    - Untitled, undated, Standard audio-cassette (Box 24, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0144)
  - Unidentified jazz recordings, undated; 139
    - not labeled, undated, Compact disc (Box 31, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0092)
    - Untitled, undated, compact disc (Box 30, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0309)
  - WCVS radio program, 1999 May; 144
    - WCVS [illegible] Beatles Westwood/Westwood One Radio May 1999/George Harrison, Ringo Star, Lori Harrison, Bob Bartel, 4-Vests/Beatle Music 60 min. Both Sides, 1999 May, audio-cassette (Box 24, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0144)
  - William Johnson Nasher Talk for JLP, undated; 145
    - William Johnson "Bill" Nasher talk for JLP exhibit, undated, DVD (Box 31, Video-disc RL10001-DVD-0001)
    - William Johnson "Bill" Nasher talk for JLP exhibit, undated, DVD (Box 31, Video-disc RL10001-DVD-0002)
  - WNYC "The Tapes" Episode, undated; 146
    - WNYC "The Tapes Episode JLP, undated, Compact disc (Box 33, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0168)
  - WNYC NEH Proposal Sample Intro, 2008; 147
    - 2008; WNYC NEH Proposal Sample Intro Radio--Jazz Loft, 2008, Compact disc (Box 35, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0246)
  - Zorro! Original Score from the Smuin Ballet World Premiere Production, undated; 148
    - Zorro! Original Score from the Smuin Ballet World Premiere Production; Music composed and conducted by Charles Fox; Performed by the Czech Philharmonic Chamber Orchestra, undated, Compact disc (Box 36, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0278)